<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<chapter xml:id="number-types" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <title>Number Types</title>

  <section xml:id="natural-numbers">
    <title>The Natural Numbers and Sets</title>

    <p>
      When we first learn to count, we begin in the natural way of doing so, starting with <m>1</m>, then <m>2</m>, and so forth.
      These numbers are referred to as the Natural numbers or counting numbers. In some cases, <m>0</m> is included in the Natural numbers,
      and other times its inclusion is called the Whole numbers. In mathematics, we refer to this collection of things as a set. The items 
      within the set are called elements or members. For example, we could say that <m>5</m> is an element of the set of Natural numbers.</p>

    <p>
      To write small sets, we use curly braces. For example, we could write a set of Natural numbers as <m>\{1, 2, 5, 7\}</m>. While this works
      well for small sets, clearly we cannot write all the Natural numbers this way. Additionally, writing "the Natural numbers" would prove 
      difficult in many contexts where they are used, so we use the symbol <m>\mathbb{N}</m> to represent the set of Natural numbers.
    </p>
    <xi:include href="./exercises/chapter-1/nat-numbers.xml" />
    
  </section>

  <section xml:id="integers">
    <title>Integers</title>
    <p>
      With the Natural numbers defined, we can think of extending the set to include negative numbers with no decimal or fractional
      component. Examples include <m>-8</m>, <m>-759</m>, and <m>42</m> (also a Natural number). We write the set of all integers as
      <m>\mathbb{Z}</m>. Notice how all the Natural numbers are also integers. We say that the Natural numbers are a subset of the 
      integers, since every Natural number is also an integer.
    </p>
    <xi:include href="./exercises/chapter-1/integers.xml" />
  </section>

  <section xml:id="rational">
    <title>Rational Numbers</title>
    <p>
        More text here
    </p>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="reals">
    <title>Real Numbers</title>
    <p>
        More text here
    </p>
  </section>
<section xml:id="chapter-1-exercises">
<title>Chapter 1 Review Exercises</title>
<xi:include href="./exercises/exercises-chapter-1.xml" />
</section>
</chapter>